Guide to the Apostles Club Records, 1894 - 1967
Apostles Club Records, 1894-1967
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Apostles Club.
1000-192
0.75
2
The Apostles Club was a group of faculty members at Wesleyan University who met once a month from 1894 until 1967 for literary and social purposes.
The bulk of the Apostles Club Records are meeting minutes, with a small amount of correspondence, clippings, and lists of members.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Received after 1967.
Historical Note
The Apostles Club was a group of faculty members at Wesleyan University who met once a month from 1894 until 1967. At each meeting one of the members or a guest would present research, followed by a discussion among the present members. On its foundation, it was, according the minutes of the first meeting, for literary and social purposes. The name The Apostles Club was adopted after a nickname referring to the number of founding members. The original faculty members were from the academic fields of literature, history, and philosophy. It was usually was hosted at one of the member's homes. The group's officers included a President, Vice President, Treasurer and a Secretary (or, if the Secretary was absent, an “ad-interim” secretary) who took notes and presented them at the next meeting to be approved by the members.
The Club ceased meeting at the end of the 1966-1967 academic year.
Collection Overview
The bulk of the Apostles Club Records are meeting minutes, which were recorded beginning in 1894 until the last meeting in 1967, although they become increasingly more detailed in later years. Up until early 1952 the minutes were recorded in journals, but after that the secretaries began to type them. The minutes specified host and presenter for each meeting, as well as the topic of discussion. In addition to minutes, there are a few pieces of correspondence from 1939, two clippings about the Apostles Club from 1895 and 1897, and lists of members between 1920 and 1965.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Apostles Club.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Faculty.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Minutes
    - December 1894-April 1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - October 1916-April 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - May 1916-October 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - November 1948-February 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Clippings from Wesleyan University Bulletin, 1895, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Members and Assignments, 1920-1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)